Let's take a closer look at how the decoder trains on a given caption.
我们仔细研究下解码器是如何用给定图像说明进行训练的
The decoder will be made of LSTM cells,
解码器由 LSTM 单元组成
which are good at remembering lengthy sequence of words.
它们擅长于记住很长的单词序列
Each LSTM cell is expecting to see the same shape of the input vector at each time-step.
每个 LSTM 单元要求在每个时间步都看到相同形状的输入向量
The very first cell is connected to the output feature vector of the CNN encoder.
第一个单元与 CNN 编码器的输出特征向量相连
Previously, I mentioned an embedding layer that transformed each input word
之前我提到 有一个嵌入层将每个输入单词
into a vector of a certain shape before being fed as input to the RNN.
变成特定形状的向量 然后再当做输入馈送到 RNN 中
We need to apply the same transformation to the output feature vector of the CNN.
我们需要对 CNN 的输出特征向量应用相同的转换
Once this feature vector is embedded into expected input shape,
将此特征向量嵌入为期望的输入形状后
we can begin that RNN training process with this as the first input.
我们就可以开始 RNN 训练流程了 并将此向量当做第一个输入
The input to the RNN for all future time steps,
在所有未来时间步 RNN 的输入将是
will be the individual words of the training caption.
训练说明的单个单词
So at the start of training,
在训练开始时
we have some input from our CNN,
我们有一些来自 CNN 的输入
and LSTM cell with the initial state.
和具有初始状态的 LSTM 单元
Now the R-net has two responsibilities.
RNN 有两项责任
One, remember spatial information from the input feature vector.
责任一是记住输入特征向量的空间信息
And two, predict the next word.
责任二是预测下个单词
We know that the very first word it produces should always be the start token,
我们知道它生成的第一个单词应该始终为起始标记
and the next word should be those in the training caption.
下个单词应该是训练说明里的单词
For our caption, a man holding a slice of pizza.
对于我们的说明“A man holding a slice of pizza.”
We know that after the start token comes a,
我们知道起始标记之后是 a
and after a comes man, and so on.
a 之后是 man 以此类推
At every time step,
在每个时间步
we look at the current caption word as input,
我们将当前说明单词作为输入
and combine it with the hidden state of the LSTM cell to produce an output.
并将其与 LSTM 单元的隐藏状态相结合 生成输出
This output is then passed through a fully connected layer that produces
这个输出然后传入全连接层
a distribution that represents the most likely next word.
生成表示概率最高的下个单词的概率分布
This is like how we've seen softmax apply to classification task.
这是将 softmax 应用到分类任务上的效果
But in this case,
但在此示例中
it produces a list of next words scores instead of a list of class scores.
它生成一个下个单词得分列表 而不是类别得分列表
We feed the next word in the caption to the network,
我们将说明中的下个单词馈送到网络中
and so on, until we reach the end token.
以此类推 直到抵达结束标记
The hidden state of an LSTM is a function of the input token to the LSTM,
LSTM 的隐藏状态是上个状态中
and the previous state.
该 LSTM 的输入标记函数
I'll refer to this function as the recurrence function.
我将此函数称为递推函数
The recurrence function is defined by weights,
递推函数由权重定义
and during the training process this model uses
在训练流程中
back propagation to update these weights until
此模型利用反向传播更新这些权重
the LSTM cells learn to produce the correct
直到 LSTM 单元学习根据给定的当前输入单词
next word in the caption given the current input word.
生成正确的下个说明单词
As with most models,
和大多数模型一样
you can also take advantage of batching the training data.
你也可以批处理训练数据
The model update its weights after each training batch with the batch size is
模型在每个训练批次之后会更新权重
the number of image caption pairs
批次大小是在一个训练步中
sent through that network during a single training step.
发送给网络的图像说明对数量
Once the model is trained,
模型训练后
it will have learned from many image caption pairs and should
它将从很多图像说明对中学习规律
be able to generate captions for new image data.
应该能够为新的图像数据生成说明